Glucksman Ireland House Records AIA.038
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Glucksman Ireland House Records
1907-2002
1993-2002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Glucksman Ireland House
AIA.038
7.4 Linear Feet in 13 legal sized manuscript boxes, 1 half letter sized manuscript box, 1 letter sized manuscript box, 1 shared CD box, 1 shared flat box, and 1 shared media box
542 Megabytes on 2 optical discs, 4 floppy disks, and 4 zip disks
The Glucksman Ireland House, established in 1993, is the center for Irish Studies at New York University. It offers undergraduate and graduate courses in history, Irish language, literature, music, and politics. The Glucksman Ireland House Records roughly span from 1907 to 2002, with the bulk of the materials dating between 1993 to 2002. The collection documents various aspects of the 1995 International Conference on Hunger sponsored by Glucksman Ireland House, social and educational events hosted by the Irish Studies Department, as well as Glucksman Ireland House's administrative activities.
Scope and Contents
The Glucksman Ireland House Records roughly span from 1907 to 2002, with the bulk of the materials dating between 1993 to 2002.
In 1995, to commemorate the 150th Anniversary of the Great Famine in Ireland, Glucksman Ireland House sponsored the International Conference on Hunger, which examined the history of famine on a global scale. Series I: International Conference on Hunger contains various materials including press releases, newspaper advertisements, budgets, meeting minutes, grant proposals and applications for conference funding, solicitations to outside corporate sponsors for conference funding, conference pre-registration and registration confirmation cards, memorandum, newspaper clippings, correspondence, profiles about conference presenters, mailing lists, as well as conference brochures and programs. This series also contains printed copies of papers presented at the conference, as well as 3 floppy disks holding digital copies of some conference papers.
Series II: Glucksman Ireland House Activities and Administrative Files focuses upon social and educational events hosted by the Irish Studies Department, as well as Glucksman Ireland House's administrative activities. These events include lecture series, commemoration dinners, and film festivals. Materials in this collection include postcards, event calendars, memorandum, course listings, brochures, ciruculars, event programs, audiovisual tapes, zip drives, floppy disks, photographs, correspondence, and newspaper clippings.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The provenance of this collection is unknown.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns. Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted.
Biographical Note
The Glucksman Ireland House, established in 1993, is the center for Irish Studies at New York University. It offers undergraduate and graduate courses in history, Irish language, literature, music, and politics. In addition to pursuing an undergraduate minor, a B.A./M.A., or an M.A. in Irish and Irish-American Studies, students at Glucksman Ireland House also have the ability to spend a summer studying abroad in Dublin, which is arranged through Glucksman Ireland House. When not convening classes, the Glucksman Ireland House also hosts weekly events and speakers on topics related to Irish politics, culture, and academia.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged into the following series:
Series I: International Conference on Hunger
Series II: Glucksman Ireland House Activities and Administrative Files
Within each series, materials are arranged in alphabetical order.
Separated Materials
Materials related to the Museum of the City of New York's "Gaelic Gotham: A History of the Irish in New York" exhibition were relocated to the New York Irish History Roundtable Records (AIA.018). Materials related to Claire Grimes were relocated to the Grimes Family Films and Other Materials collection (AIA.040).
Conferences.; Brochures.; Correspondence.; Colloquia and conference papers; VHS; Betacam-SP.; Mini-DV.; Floppy disks.; CD-Rs.; Irish Americans.; Famine.; Ireland -- History -- Famine, 1845-1852; Administrative records.; Irish studies; Film festivals.; Art -- Exhibitions.; Photographs.; Glucksman Ireland House
- Series I: International Conference on Hunger, 1993-1996; 3.5 Linear Feet in 8 legal sized manuscript boxes and 1 shared media box; 4.5 Megabytes on 3 floppy disks
  Scope and Contents
  In 1995, to commemorate the 150th Anniversary of the Great Famine in Ireland, Glucksman Ireland House sponsored and hosted the International Conference on Hunger, which examined the history of famine on a global scale. Glucksman Ireland House also coordinated the creation of a small exhibition focused on the Great Famine that was displayed concurrent with the conference.
  Series I: International Conference on Hunger contains various materials including press releases, newspaper advertisements, budgets, meeting minutes, grant proposals and applications for conference funding, solicitations to outside corporate sponsors for conference funding, conference pre-registration and registration confirmation cards, memorandum, newspaper clippings, correspondence, profiles about conference presenters, mailing lists, as well as conference brochures and programs. This series also contains printed copies of papers presented at the conference, as well as 3 floppy disks holding digital copies of some conference papers.
  It should be noted in this series, although folders 18-21 contain the word "video" in the title, these folders do not contain any audiovisual materials. These folders only contain papers.
  - '95 Famine Conference, 1993; cuid35048 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Address List, undated; cuid35049 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Advertising, 1994-1995; cuid35050 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Allan Cubbit, 1995; cuid35051 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Express, 1994; cuid35052 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Archer Daniels Midland, 1994; cuid35053 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Art Exhibits, undated; cuid35054 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Articles on Famine, 1994; cuid35055 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Asbjorn Eide, 1995; cuid35056 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bibliography, undated; cuid35057 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bookselling at Conference, 1995; cuid35058 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - British Council, 1994; cuid35059 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Brochure Design/Printing, 1994-1995; cuid35060 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Budget (incl. codes), 1995; cuid35061 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Clinical Aspects of Famine (Kevin M. Cahill, MD), undated; cuid35062 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Compassion Fatigue and Famine Relief in Imperial China (Peter C. Perdue), 1995; cuid35063 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Computer Files related to Hunger Conference, 1995; cuid35347; 320 kilobytes (Box Electronic Records, Disk TW_AIA_038_ER_1)
  - The Condition of Famine Immigrants in Antebellum New York (Alan M. Kraut), 1995; cuid35064 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Conf. 2 Page Description, undated; cuid35065 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Conf. Contact List (Master), 1994; cuid35066 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Conf. Correspondence - NOT re: speakers, 1994-1995; cuid35067 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Conf. Detailed Narrative, 1994; cuid35068 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Conf. General Proposal, 1994; cuid35069 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Conference Planning Mtgs, 1994; cuid35070 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Conference Presentation List, undated; cuid35071 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Conference Schedule, 1995; cuid35072 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Conference Transcripts Inquiries, 1995; cuid35073 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Conference Work Plan, undated; cuid35074 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Diet, Subsistence, Crises and Hunger before the Great Irish Famine (David Dickson), 1995; cuid35075 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Dr. Deborah Toler, 1995; cuid35076 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Dr. Ellen Messer, 1994-1995; cuid35077 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Dr. J. Larry Brown, 1994-1995; cuid35078 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Dr. Kevin M. Cahill, 1994-1995; cuid35079 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Dr. Kevin Whelan, 1994-1995; cuid35080 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Dr. Laurence M. Geary, 1994-1996; cuid35081 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Dr. Martin H. Geyer, 1994-1995; cuid35082 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Dr. Peter Gray, 1995-1996; cuid35083 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Dr. Sophia Hillian King, 1994-1995; cuid35084 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Famine Conference Funding, 1994; cuid35085 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Famine Conference - General Correspondence, 1994; cuid35086 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Famine Conference Masters, undated; cuid35087 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Famine - Correspondence Panels, 1994-1995; cuid35088 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Famine, Disease, and Famine Mortality: lessons from the Irish Experience, 1845-1850 (Joel Mokyr), 1995; cuid35089 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The Famine in Dublin City (Cormac O Grada), 1995; cuid35090 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Famine, Entitlements, and Seduction: Captain Edmond Wynne in Ireland, 1846-1851, undated; cuid35091 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Famine and Epidemic Disease in Nineteenth Century Ireland: The Psychological and Social Impact (Laurence M. Geary), 1995; cuid35092 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Famine and Its Discourse (Denis Donoghue), undated; cuid35093 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Famine Museum of Ireland, 1995; cuid35094 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The Famine Process and the Phasing of Interventions (John Osgood Field), 1995; cuid35095 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Famine Relief in Comparative Perspective: Ireland, Scotland, and North-Western Europe, 1845-50 (Peter Gray), undated; cuid35096 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Ford Foundation, 1994-1995; cuid35097 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - The Great Famine and Women's Emigration from Ireland (Janet Nolan), 1995; cuid35098 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Heinz Co. Foundation, 1994; cuid35099 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Hotels - Other/general, 1995; cuid35100 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Hunger Conference: Press Clippings, 1995; cuid35101 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Hunger and History: The Great Irish Famine in Global Context, Proceedings of the Ireland House International Conference on Hunger, 1995; cuid35102 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Hunger and Human Rights (Asbjorn Eide and Wenche Barth Eide), 1995; cuid35103 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Hunger Project, 1994; cuid35104 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Income/Expense Report, 1995; cuid35105 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - International Conference on Hunger 19/20 May 1995 Selected Audience Comments, cuid35106 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - International Conference on Hunger Booklet, 1995; cuid35107 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - International Conferene on Hunger Confirmation of Participation, 1995; cuid35108 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - International Conference on Hunger Folder Pack, 1995; cuid35109 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - International Conference on Hunger Keynote Address by President Mary Robinson, 1995; cuid35110 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - International Conference on Hunger Pre-Registration Card, undated; cuid35111 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - International Conference on Hunger Program, undated; cuid35112 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - International Conference on Hunger Stickers, 1995; cuid35113 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Ireland House/International Conference on Hunger May 19 & 20, 1995, cuid35114 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Irish Americaqn Heritage Museum, 1994-1995; cuid35115 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Irish Cultural Relations Cttee, 1995; cuid35116 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Joel Charny, 1995; cuid35117 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Letters of Support, undated; cuid35118 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Liverpool in Black '47 (R Scally), 1995; cuid35119 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Local Response to the Great Famine: a questions of competence? (Mary Daly), 1995; cuid35120 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Loeb Student Center, 1994-1995; cuid35121 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Luke Dodd, 1994-1995; cuid35122 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Mailing List, 1994-1995; cuid35123 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
  - Mailing List Memos/Orders, 1994; cuid35124 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Malnutrition and the Culture of Food Consumption in Brazil: a Historical View (Robert Levine), 1995; cuid35125 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Master List of Speakers, 1995; cuid35126 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - The Memory of Hunger (David Lloyd), undated; cuid35127 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Michael Quigley, 1995; cuid35128 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Michael Sheridan, 1994-1995; cuid35129 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - "The Most Irish City in the Union": The Era of the Great Migration 1844-1877 (Hasia Diner), 1995; cuid35130 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Mr. Michael Lally, 1995; cuid35131 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Mr. Peter Quinn, 1995; cuid35132 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Museums, 1994; cuid35133 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Names in the News, 1993-1994; cuid35134 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - NEH - Draft Application, 1994; cuid35135 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - NEH Final Application, 1994; cuid35136 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - NEH Follow-Up, 1995; cuid35137 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - NEH Guidelines, 1991-1996; cuid35138 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - New York Times Foundation, 1994; cuid35139 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - NYCH - Grant Acceptance, undated; cuid35140 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - NYCH - Grant Application, 1994; cuid35141 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - NYCH - Guidelines, 1994; cuid35142 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - NY Council on Humanities, 1994; cuid35143 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - NYU Guest Services, 1995; cuid35144 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - The Origins of Hunger in Latin America: An Overview (Robert Marx Delson), 1995; cuid35145 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Other Potential Funds, 1993-1995; cuid35146 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The Pauper and the Politician: A Tale of Two Immigrants and the Construction of Irish-American Society (Kerby A Miller & Bruce D. Boling), 1995; cuid35147 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Photographer Fergus Bourke, 1994; cuid35148 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Pictures Drawn from Memory: William Carleton's Experience of Famine (Sophia Hillan King), 1995; cuid35149 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - The Politics of the Famine in Eastern Ukraine, 1946-1947 (Amir Weiner), 1995; cuid35150 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Postmodern Hunger: The United States (Marion Nestle), 1995; cuid35151 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Proceedings of the Ireland House Hunger Conference (Draft), 1995; cuid35152 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Prof. Alan M. Kraut, 1995; cuid35153 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Prof. Amartya Sen, 1994-1995; cuid35154 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Prof. Amir Weiner, 1995; cuid35155 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Prof. Aristide Zollberg, 1995; cuid35156 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Prof. Carl Riskin, 1994-1996; cuid35157 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Prof. Christopher Mitchell, 1994-1995; cuid35158 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Prof. Cormac O'Grada, 1994-1995; cuid35159 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Prof. Cynthia Bouton, 1994-1995; cuid35160 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Prof. David Dickson, 1995-1996; cuid35161 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Prof. David Doyle, 1995; cuid35162 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Prof. David Fitzpatrick, 1994-1995; cuid35163 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Prof. David Lloyd, 1995-1996; cuid35164 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Prof. Denis Donoghue, 1994-1995; cuid35165 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Prof. Dorothy Nelkin, 1993-1996; cuid35166 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Prof. Hasia R. Diner, 1994-1996; cuid35167 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Prof. James S. Donnelly, 1993-1995; cuid35168 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Prof. Janet Nolan, 1994-1995; cuid35169 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Prof. Joel Mokyr, 1994-1996; cuid35170 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Prof. John Bohstedt, undated; cuid35171 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Prof. John Osgood Field, 1994-1995; cuid35172 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Prof. Kerby Miller, 1993-1995; cuid35173 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Prof. Leslie Clarkson, 1994-1995; cuid35174 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Prof. Liz Young, 1994-1995; cuid35175 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Prof. Lucile F. Newman, 1994-1996; cuid35176 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Prof. Luke Gibbons, 1995; cuid35177 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Prof. Marion Nestle, 1994-1995; cuid35178 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Prof. Mary E. Daly, 1994-1995; cuid35179 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Prof. Peter Perdue, 1994-1996; cuid35180 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Prof. Richard Hull, 1994-1996; cuid35181 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Prof. Robert Levine, 1994-1996; cuid35182 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Prof. Roberta Delson, 1995-1996; cuid35183 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Prof. Stephen Wheatcroft, 1995-1996; cuid35184 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Prof. Terry Eagleton, 1994-1995; cuid35185 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Prof. Walton Johnson, 1995; cuid35186 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Prof. Yanni Kotsonis, 1995; cuid35187 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Proposal Forms (Evan Newfeld), undated; cuid35188 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Public Affairs/Barbara Jester, 1994-1995; cuid35189 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Public Policy, Private Lives: Famine Relief and Community in India (Lucile F. Newman), 1995; cuid35190 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Requests for Papers, Tapes of Proceedings, 1995; cuid35191 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Resumes, undated; cuid35192 (Box 7, Folder 22-23)
  - Richard G. Robbins, 1995-1996; cuid35193 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - The Russian Famine of 1891-1892: Administrative Response to Social Crises (Richard G. Robbins Jr.), 1995; cuid35194 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Russian and Soviet Famines and Food Problems, 1890-1940 (Stephen G. Wheatcraft), 1995; cuid35195 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Science and Hunger: The Problematic Promises of a Technological Fix (Dorothy Nelkin), 1995; cuid35196 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Six Questions About the Chinese Famine of 1959-61 (Carl Riskin), 1995; cuid35197 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Spaces for Famine: A Comparative Geographical Analysis of Famine in Ireland and the Highlands in the 1840s (Liz Young), 1995; cuid35198 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Speakers -- Canceled, 1994-1995; cuid35199 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Special Events, undated; cuid35200 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Sponsored Research - Correspondence, Codes, etc, 1994-1995; cuid35201 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Starvation and Political Economy: Famines, Entitlements, and Alienation (Amartya Sen), 1995; cuid35202 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Summary Preservation on the Cambodia Famine 1975-1981, 1995; cuid35203 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Sylivia's "To Do" File, 1994-1995; cuid35204 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Three Great Famines: Causes and Consequences (Richard W. Hull), 1995; cuid35205 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Tim Robinson, 1994-1995; cuid35206 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Transcription, undated; cuid35207 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Travel, 1995; cuid35208 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Veatch Program (U.U.), undated; cuid35209 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Video - Correspondence, also videos rejected, 1995; cuid35210 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Video - "The Hanging Gale", 1995; cuid35211 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Video - Notes on Individual Places, 1995; cuid35212 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Video - Technical and Ordering Info, undated; cuid35213 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Washington Square Hotel, 1995; cuid35214 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Weeping for Connemara (Tim Robinson), 1995; cuid35215 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Wild Geese, 1994; cuid35216 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Series II: Glucksman Ireland House Activities and Administrative Files, 1907-2002 (inclusive); 1991-2002 (bulk); 3.77 Linear Feet in 5 legal sized manuscript boxes, 1 letter sized manuscript box, 1 half letter sized manuscript box, 1 shared media box, 1 shared CD box, and 1 shared flat box; 1.70 Gigabytes on 4 zip disks, 2 optical discs, and 1 floppy disk
  This series focuses upon the many social and educational events hosted by the Irish Studies Department such as the Ballinglen Art exhibit, the "Framing Her Image: Women in Irish Film" festival, the "Gothic, the National, the Subversive" Symposium on the Irish Gothic, and the Seamus Heaney Dinner. This series also focuses upon Glucksman Ireland House's administrative activities such as seeking funding to sustain Ireland House, hiring new faculty, budgetary meetings, and curriculum development. Finally, this series includes a large number of interview and promotional audiovisual tape.
  Materials in this series consist of postcards, event calendars, memorandum, course listings, brochures, ciruculars, event programs, VHS Tapes, miniDV tapes, Betacam SP tapes, DVcam tapes, zip drives, floppy disks, photographs, correspondence, and newspaper clippings.
  - 001 AIA - K. Mulvey, D.H. Cudahy, 1999; cuid35217 (Box 16, Minidv 038.0029)
  - 002 AIA - K. Mulvey, D.H. Cudahy, 1999; cuid35218 (Box 16, Minidv 038.0030)
  - 003 AIA - Rita Fitzpatrick #1, 2000; cuid35219 (Box 16, Minidv 038.0031)
  - 004 AIA - Rita Fitzpatrick #2, 2000; cuid35220 (Box 16, Minidv 038.0032)
  - 005 AIA - Rita Fitzpatrick #3, 2000; cuid35221 (Box 16, Minidv 038.0033)
  - 006 AIA - Rita Fitzpatrick #4/Rosaleen Fitzgibbon #1, 2000; cuid35222 (Box 16, Minidv 038.0034)
  - 007 AIA - Rosaleen Fitzgibbon #2, 2000; cuid35223 (Box 16, Minidv 038.0035)
  - 008 AIA - Rosaleen Fitzgibbon #3, 2000; cuid35224 (Box 16, Minidv 038.0036)
  - 009 AIA - Rosaleen Fitzgibbon #4, 2000; cuid35225 (Box 16, Minidv 038.0037)
  - 2nd Avenue Online, undated; cuid35226 (Box 15, Vhs 038.0014)
  - AIA Campus Shots, 2000; cuid35227 (Box 16, Minidv 038.0043)
  - American Ireland Funds, 1994; cuid35228 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - American Irish Hist-Society, 1993; cuid35229 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - The Archives of Irish America at New York University, undated; cuid35230 (Box 14, Vhs 038.0002)
  - Archives of Irish America Promo NYU Ireland House 6 June 2000 Tape #1, cuid35231 (Box 14, Vhs 038.0003)
  - Archives of Irish America Promo NYU Ireland House 6 June 2000 Tape #2, cuid35232 (Box 14, Vhs 038.0004)
  - Archives of Irish America Promo NYU Ireland House 6 June 2000 Tape #3, cuid35233 (Box 14, Vhs 038.0005)
  - Archives of Irish America Promo NYU Ireland House 6 June 2000 Tape #4, cuid35234 (Box 14, Vhs 038.0006)
  - Arts Cassidy - Laur Cassidy, 1994; cuid35235 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Background Materials - Glucksman Ireland House & the Irish Studies Program, 1994-1999; cuid35236 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Ballinglen Art Exhibit, 1998-1999; cuid35237 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - The Ballinglen Experience, 1999; cuid35238 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - A Budget Proposal for the "Irish Curriculum Committee", 1997; cuid35239 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Carlow & Roscommon, 1907, 1940-1941; cuid35240 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "Coming Times: New Irish Cinema" program, 1999; cuid35241 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Computer Files and Photographs related to Glucksman Ireland House, 1999-2000; cuid35348; 541 Megabytes (Box Electronic Records, Disk TW_AIA_038_ER_2)
  - Concern WW, 1993-1994; cuid35242 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Cooperation Ireland, 1992-1993; cuid35243 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Cormac O'Malley 1, Loretta Brennan Glucksman NYU Ireland House CR #1, 2000; cuid35244 (Box 16, Minidv 038.0038)
  - Correspondence, 1995-1999; cuid35245 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Eileen Zurell, undated; cuid35246 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - English Dept. Visting Scholars, 1996; cuid35247 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - European Exchange, 1995; cuid35248 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - European Studies, 1994-1995; cuid35249 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - An Evening with Seamus Heaney, 1996; cuid35250 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Exce Board, 1995; cuid35251 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Fall 1993 IH Program, cuid35252 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Famine - Media Conf., 1994; cuid35253 (Box 9, Folder 19)